I've always had a penchant for creativity. My life has been a continual exploration of mediums ranging from textiles and metalsmithing to designing for editorial publications, both print and digital.

As a Software Engineer, my focus is on exploring this medium of computer programming - applying my creative and technical problem-solving skills as well as my tenacious spirit. Because of my previous work environment, I'm adept at prioritizing key deliverables under tight deadlines and collaborating effectively across departments.

SKILLS

JavaScript | CSS | HTML | React | Redux | Ruby on Rails | RESTful APIs | Adobe Creative Cloud

PROJECTS

Adopt a Pet, a React app. GITHUB FRONTEND | GITHUB BACKEND | DEMO

an app for adopting/maintaining a virtual pet without the upkeep of a live one
Persists each user's pets and experience to a Postgres database and provides a Rails API with JWT authorization.
Displays a React frontend with Semantic-ui-React and CSS. Employs flexbox with hamburger menu

Come on Kayak, a React-Redux app. GITHUB FRONTEND | GITHUB BACKEND | DEMO

an app for kayakers to make comments on past trips and create upcoming ones

Persists data to a Rails database and provides a Rails API. Displays a React, Redux frontend with Semantic-ui-React.

Fetches data from the Rails API using Javascript

Earth Paints, a React app. GITHUB FRONTEND | GITHUB BACKEND | DEMO

an app to discover images that Google Earth takes from afar

Persists data to a Rails database and provides a Rails API. Incorporates a search bar to sort by Country. Displays a React frontend with Semantic UI React. Fetches data from the Rails API using Javascript.

Match Game, a vanilla Javascript app. GITHUB I DEMO

a memory game app Built with vanilla Javacript, CSS, HTML.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Freelance Web Developer | August 2019-Present Freelance Print, Digital Art Director | June 2017-Present

Various Clients ranging from Publications to Individuals

Digital Art Director | September 2011-May 2017

Hearst | Women's Health | Prevention | People Magazine

all located in New York, NY

Reviewed content from print material and translated it using elements of company's designated brand for user interaction on ipad/iphone. Utilized Edge Animate and Photoshop to produce engaging interactive material for the reader. Redesigned ipad/iphone editions to reflect current format to insure continued viewing by subscribers. Directed staff of 4, troubleshot design decisions to improve layout to best captivate and maintain readers' attention

Art Director | April 1996-August 2011

Shape Magazine | Time Inc. Custom Publishing | TV Guide | Worth Magazine all located in New York, NY

Produced effective layouts, contributed to multiple redesigns under high pressure environment; met deadlines on or ahead of schedule while continuously updating content based on feedback. Collaborated with editors to visualize their perception of stories; independently created end products. Conceptualized story content with illustrators to determine visual representation; hired talent based on whether subject matter and illustrator/photographer specialization were aligned

Awarded for outstanding design by:

Print's Best Typography | PRINT'S Regional Design Annual | The Society of Publication Design

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, New York, NY | Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript immersive program General Assembly, New York, NY | Front-end web development

New School University, New York, NY | Non matriculated coursework on HTML, web design

New York University, New York, NY | Dreamweaver coursework

Kansas University, Lawrence, KS | Bachelor of Fine Arts in Visual Communications

